SHRUTI KUMARI

JAVA DEVELOPER

shrutikumariwork@gmail.com +91-6361525201

2 years experienced java development professional with a prolific track record of designing, testing, and monitoring software as well as upgrading the existing programs.

Proficient in interacting with the key clients, understanding their requirements to complete projects within stipulated time & budget, and ensuring optimum client satisfaction.

WORK HISTORY

Java Developer

TREXEDIA TRAVEL TECHNOLOGY, INDIA PVT. LTD, BENGALURU 2021-09 - Present

- Handled the main SBT team which is totally responsible for backend development using Java 8, J2EE and REST/SOAP API Calls, Apache TOMCAT.
- Also worked for ERP team which works for UI using JSF Primefaces, XHTML ,CSS,ThymeLeaf .
- Designed, implemented, and maintained Java application phases and assisted in software & Spring MVC architectural development using Java SpringBoot.
- Implemented the product's lifecycle including designing, development, debugging, deployment, and maintenance using Jenkins.
- Recommended changes to enhance Java application processes and maintained & updated existing J2EE
- Collaborated effectively across cross-functional teams like SBT ,ERP and INVOICING.

INTERNSHIP

Clinical SAS Programming INTERN

2021-02 - 2021-08

LABCORP, BENGALURU

- Learnt Clinical Programming using Clinical SAAS and Oracle INFORM.
- Implemented C#.

SKILLS

- RESTful and SOAP API development, Spring MVC, JSF Primefaces
- Core Java, Spring Boot and related frameworks
- Java 6& 8, J2EE, Eclipse, HTML, CSS, JSF
- Framework & Web Services: JAXB, JPA, JavaEE, Spring
- Database Management: MySQL, mongodb
- Microservices ,Webservices
- TOMCAT ,Jenkins

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications

2018-10 - 2021-08

RV COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, BENGALURU 8.29 CGPA